Guide to the Robert L. Patten: George Cruikshank research materials, 1792 - 2002, bulk 1836-1977 MS 493
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Robert L. Patten: George Cruikshank research materials
1792-2002
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Patten, Robert L., 1939-
MS 493
52 Linear Feet
Typescripts, correspondence, sketches, autographs, articles, notes and other research material relating to George Cruikshank's career as an illustrator as well as his personal and family life. Robert L. Patten's two volume work, George Cruikshank's Life, Times, and Art> is a comprehensive study of the life and art of George Cruikshank.
(113 boxes)
Biographical Sketch
George Cruikshank, born in London on September 27, 1792 to a Scottish painter, Isaac Cruikshank, and his wife, was an English humorist and illustrator. Briefly educated at Edgeware, he is considered by some to be one of the best humorists that Britain ever produced. Cruikshank began his career as a political satirist but moved on to become a book illustrator. He also had a late interest in oil painting, enrolling in the Academy Schools as a student at the age of sixty-four. In his lifetime he created nearly 10,000 prints, illustrations, and plates. His early drawings often featured attacks on Britain's royal family. In the 1820s his preoccupation with political caricature waned, however, as he became more interested in theatrical caricatures and book illustrations. Cruikshank produced some of his best-known work for Charles Dickens, beginning with Sketches by Boz, (1836) and reaching an apex with Oliver Twist, (1838). Grimm's Fairy Tales, Pilgrim's Progress, Paradise Lost, and seven novels by William Harrison Ainsworth were among other works he illustrated.
Cruikshank married Mary Ann Walker (1807-1849) on October 16, 1827. Two years after her death, on March 7, 1851, he married Eliza Widdison. Later in his life, Cruikshank supported the temperance movement, creating prints illustrating the evils of alcohol. Collections of his works are in the British and the Victoria and Albert museums. George Cruikshank died February 1, 1878.
Robert L. Patten, the Lynette S. Autrey Professor of Humanities at Rice University, was born on April 26, 1939 in Oklahoma City. He received his B.A. from Swarthmore College in 1960. He went on to earn an M.A. (1962) and Ph.D. (1965) from Princeton University. After college, Patten lectured in English at Bryn Mawr College, leaving there in 1969 to take a position as Assistant Professor in the English Department at Rice University, where he became a full professor in 1976. In 1991 and 1992 Patten chaired Rice's English Department. The author of dozens of articles and reviews on nineteenth-century British literature, Patten used the materials in this collection to write a two-volume biography of George Cruikshank, entitled George Cruikshank's Life, Times, and Art (vol. 1, 1992; vol. 2, 1996). In 1999 The Guardian, a British newspaper, called Patten's biography one of the best books of the 1990s.
Robert L. Patten was a Fulbright Scholar from 1963 to 1964 and a Guggenheim Fellow in 1980. He was also chosen as a Couper Scholar in 2004, served as president of the Rice University Chapter of Phi Beta Kappa from 1991 to 1994 and 1997 to 2002, and chaired the Dickens Society in 1973 and 1974. Patten has served in numerous capacities at Rice University, including the Sallyport Award Committee (1986-87), the Advisory Committee on Parking (1992-94), and the University Review Board (1982-84). In addition to George Cruikshank's Life, Times, and Art, Patten is the author of Charles Dickens and His Publishers(1978), and editor of George Cruikshank: A Revaluation(1974) and Literature in the Marketplace: Nineteenth-Century British Publishing and Reading Practices (1995). He also serves as editor of Studies in English Literature and founded and briefly edited the periodical Dickens Studies Newsletter.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains typescripts, page proofs, research material, correspondence, photographs and artwork relating to Robert Patten's comprehensive work on the life of George Cruikshank, entitled, George Cruikshank's Life, Times, and Art.
The first series contains material relating to the writing and production of the book, including typescripts, proofs and correspondence with publishing house Rutgers University Press and others, administrative materials and artwork.
The second series contains card file research notes, listing works, correspondence notes (name of correspondents, subject of correspondence (ex. art related, business, personal), location of repository and dates, bibliographical information, subject files and source notes.
Series three includes research material, notes, photocopies of works and articles, catalogs, correspondence, photographic materials, and subject files. Research material, primarily notes and transcriptions of correspondence, from repositories such as Princeton University, Harvard, UCLA and others are included. Collectors Frank S. Bradburn and the artist, Ronald Searle are also represented. The series holds a collection of articles relating to Cruikshank and book illustration and a series of lectures by Robert Patten.
Series four includes prints, pamphlets and illustrations including etchings, engravings and woodcuts. Many are single leaves or a series of leaves from books illustrated by Cruikshank, others are bound or loosely bound books and pamphlets. Still others are proofs (some mounted) on India paper. Many of Cruikshank's works are represented, including illustrations for Oliver Twist and Sketches by Boz (Charles Dickens), W.H. Ainsworth's novels, the Comic Almanack and other illustrations and caricatures.
Series five includes manuscript materials by and about George Cruikshank. Several collectors are represented, including Frank S. Bradburn, Christopher C. Kohler, Ronald Searle, and a number of letters, documents and ephemera obtained through Sotheby's (David Borowitz collection).
Restrictions on Access
This material is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Provenance
This collection was donated by Robert L. Patten in 1999.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following five series:
Missing Title
Series I: George Cruikshank's Life, Times, and Art production files, 1975 - 2001
Series II: Research index card files, 1792-1878
Series III: Research photocopies and notes, 1810-2002
Series IV: Prints, pamphlets, illustrations, paintings and plates, 1807-1988
Series V: Manuscripts, correspondence and other materials by and about George Cruikshank, 1811-1976
Related Materials
See Cruikshank letters, 1845 and 1868, MS 297, Woodson Research Center.
Index Terms
Subjects
Artists -- England -- History -- 19th century; Social life and customs; Caricatures and cartoons -- England; Temperance
Document Types
Illustrations; corrrespondence; etchings (prints); photographs; manuscripts (document genre); typescripts
Subjects (Persons)
Cruikshank, Isaac, 1756?-1811; Cruikshank, George, 1792-1878; Cruikshank, Eliza (Mrs. George), 1807-1849; Ainsworth, William Harrison, 1805-1882; Patten, Robert L., 1939-; Dickens, Charles, 1812-1870; Cruikshank, Robert, 1789-1856
- Series I. George Cruikshank's Life, Times, and Art production files, 1975 - 2001, 236168; (20 boxes)
  - Sub-series A: Typescripts and page proofs, circa 1980-1995, 236226
    - This sub-series contains typescripts for the book, George Cruikshank's Life Times and Art, volumes 1 and 2. The typescripts were completed by 1989, 236260
    - Illustrations (photocopies), 236259 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Typescript, preface, 236258 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Typescript, prologue, 236257 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Typescript, chapter 1-26, 236256 (Box 1, Folder 4-29)
    - Typescript, chapter 27-34, 236255 (Box 2, Folder 1-10)
    - Typescript, chapter 35-46, 236254 (Box 3, Folder 1-12)
    - Typescript, chapter 47-48, 236253 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
    - Typescript, epilogue, 236252 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Typescript, bibliography, emendata, 236251 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Typescript, genealogy, 236250 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Typescript, transcriptions and references, 236249 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Typescript, endnotes (preface – chapter 10), 236248 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Typescript, endnotes (chapter 11 – 24), 236247 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Typescript, captions for illustrations, 236246 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Typescript, general index (vol. 2), 236245 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Prologue, Chapter 1, editor's instructions, 1991 December 17, 236244 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Author's proof, 1st pass, front matter-chapter 18, 1992 March 27, April 6-7, 236243 (Box 4, Folder 12-21)
    - Author's proof, 1st pass, chapter 19-24, 1992 April 7-8, 236242 (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
    - Author's proof, 1st pass, Appendix, notes, 1992 April 8, 236241 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Author's proof, vol. 2, front matter-chapter 25-48, 1995 September 19, 236240 (Box 5, Folder 5-17)
    - Author's proof, vol. 2, transcriptions and references, 1995 September 19, 236239 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Author's proof, vol. 2, epilogue, genealogy, 1995 September 19, 236238 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Author's proof, vol. 2, notes, 1995 September 19, 236237 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Author's proof, vol. 2, general index, 1995 September 19, 236236 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Author's proof, vol. 2, front matter - chapter 25-48, 1995 December 6, 236235 (Box 6, Folder 1-13)
    - Author's proof, vol. 2, epilogue, emendata, transcriptions and references, 1995 December 6, 236234 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Author's proof, vol. 2, notes, 1995 December 6, 236233 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Typescript (copy 1), vol. 2, with editor's marks, front matter - chapter 25-48, 1995, 236232 (Box 7, Folder 1-13)
    - Typescript (copy 1), vol. 2, with editor's marks, epilogue, emendata, 1995, 236231 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Typescript (copy 1), vol. 2, with editor's marks, notes, chapter 25-31, 1995, 236230 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Typescript (copy 1), vol. 2, with editor's marks, notes, chapter 32-41, 1995, 236229 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Typescript (copy 1), vol. 2, with editor's marks, notes, chapter 42-48, 1995, 236228 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Typescript (copy 1), vol. 2, with editor's marks, bibliography, author sketch, 1995, 236227 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Sub-series B: Notes and source materials, circa 1975- 1989, 236210
    - This sub-series includes notes, articles, annotations and drafts for volumes one and two of George Cruikshank's Life, Times, and Art. The material is undated; however, most would have been generated between 1975 and 1989., 236225
    - Titles, illustrations, volume 1, 236224 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Illustrations, volume 2, 236223 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Preface, volume 1, 236222 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Prologue, volume 1, 236221 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 1 - 6, 236220 (Box 8, Folder 5-10)
    - Chapter 7-14, 236219 (Box 9, Folder 1-8)
    - Chapter 15-23, 236218 (Box 10, Folder 1-9)
    - Chapter 24-28, 236217 (Box 11, Folder 1-5)
    - Chapter 29-34, 236216 (Box 12, Folder 1-6)
    - Chapter 35-46, 236215 (Box 13, Folder 1-12)
    - Chapter 47-48, 236214 (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
    - Epilogue, 236213 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Bibliography notes, 236212 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous notes and articles, 236211 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Sub-series C: Correspondence, reviews and administrative materials, 1975-2001, 236189
    - This sub-series contains correspondence between Robert Patten and persons and institutions affiliated with the publishing of the book, George Cruikshank's Life, Times, and Art. The majority of the correspondence is with Rutger's University Press. Other materials in the sub-series include correspondence between Robert Patten and his editors, expense reports, book reviews and permissions information., 236209
    - Correspondence, British Museum, February 27, 1978 - July 23, 1985, 236208 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, Cambridge University Press, 1989 - 1990, 236207 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, Lutterworth Press, 1992, 1996, 236206 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, Oxford University Press, June 10, 1975 - November 23, 1990, 236205 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, Rutgers University Press, April 16, 1990 - November 13, 1993, 236204 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, Rutgers University Press, January 5, 1994 - July 17, 1999, 236203 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - University of Maryland, 1979 February - March, 236202 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, Yale Center for British Art publications, 1989, 236201 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Other correspondents, 1987 December 14 - 2001 June 4, 236200 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Advertisements for Cruikshank materials, 1977 - 1978, 236199 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Book expenses, account book, 1977-1979, 236198 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Book expenses, receipts and invoices, 1975 August 24 - 1979 October 29, 236197 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Book ideas and notes, undated, 236196 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Collection inventories, 1975 March - 1977 June, 236195 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Literature quotations, undated, 236194 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Permissions, rights information, 1978-1978, 1990-1995, 236193 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Reviews, 1992-1998, 236192 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Reviews, 1992 October - 1999 May, 236191 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Styling principles and techniques, undated, 236190 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Sub-series D: Art reproductions, slides, negatives and computer disks, 236169
    - This sub-series includes reproductions (glossy prints) of a number of George Cruikshank's etchings and wood-engravings produced during the years 1809-1878. Many of these prints were used to illustrate the two-volume book. Negatives and color slides of Cruikshank's artwork are among the holdings. Slides of works by artists Thomas Rowlandson and James Gillray are included. The prints were obtained from a number of repositories. The floppy disks include book chapter material and are 5 ¼ in. disks., 236188
    - Illustrations (photocopies), 236187 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Glossy prints (Vol. 1 illustrations), Frontispiece - #20, 236186 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Glossy prints (Vol. 1 illustrations), #21 – 45, 236185 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Glossy prints (Vol. 1 illustrations), #46 – 81, 236184 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Glossy prints (Vol. 2 illustrations), Frontispiece - #17, 236183 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Glossy prints (Vol. 2 illustrations), #18 – 37, 236182 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Glossy prints (Vol. 2 illustrations), #38 – 55, 236181 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Glossy prints (Vol. 2 illustrations), #56 – 81, 236180 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Glossy prints, negatives, book jacket designs, 236179 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Glossy prints, 236178 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Glossy prints, contact sheets, 236177 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Negatives (35 mm) of illustrations, 236176 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Glossy prints, includes works from Sketches by Boz, 236175 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Book jacket illustration, "Monmouth Street," Sketches by Boz, 236174 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Glossy prints from Sunday in London, 236173 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Glossy prints, contact sheets, 236172 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Slides (many in color), including illustrations used in Cruikshank's Life, Times and Art., 236171 (Box 19)
    - Peer review of Emily Allen Essay, footnotes on A Christmas Carol, 236170 (Box 20)
- Series II: Research index card files, 1792-1878, 236149; (18 boxes); This series contains card file research notes, listing works, correspondence notes (name of correspondents, subject of correspondence (ex. art related, business, personal), location of repository and dates, bibliographical information, subject files and source notes.
  - Cruikshank works, 1792-1815, 236167 (Box 21)
  - Cruikshank works, 1816-1824, 236166 (Box 22)
  - Cruikshank works, 1825-1878, 236165 (Box 23)
  - Autographs and correspondence notes, 1792-1845, 236164 (Box 24)
  - Autographs and correspondence notes, 1846-1856, 236163 (Box 25)
  - Autographs and correspondence notes, 1857-1865, 236162 (Box 26)
  - Autographs and correspondence notes, 1866-1870, 236161 (Box 27)
  - Autographs and correspondence notes, 1871-1874, 236160 (Box 28)
  - Autographs and correspondence notes, 1875-1878, funeral correspondence, 1878-1890, 236159 (Box 29)
  - Autographs and correspondence notes, undated, 236158 (Box 30)
  - Autographs and correspondence notes, 1821-1876, undated, 236157 (Box 31)
  - Autographs and correspondence notes, A-Z, 236156 (Box 32)
  - Autographs and correspondence notes, A-Z, 236155 (Box 33)
  - Catalogs, locations of works by state, California - Washington, 236154 (Box 34)
  - Subject files, Advertisements – Worship of Bacchus, 236153 (Box 35)
  - Source references, A-Z, 236152 (Box 36)
  - Bibliography, A-Z, 236151 (Box 37)
  - Bibliography (catalogs, books, criticism, drawings, miscellaneous), 236150 (Box 38)
- Series III: Research photocopies and notes, 1810-2002, 235696; (27 boxes)
  - This series includes research material, notes, photocopies of works and articles, catalogs, correspondence, photographic materials, and subject files., 236148
  - Sub-series A: Correspondence, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent or organization. General correspondence in the first two folders, 1966-1997, 236125
    - General correspondence, A-M, 1974 September - 1989 June, 236147 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - General correspondence, N-Z, 1975 June 1 - 1987 December, 236146 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Bell and Hyman Ltd., undated, 236145 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Bradburn, Frank, 1970 June 16 - 1982 February, 236144 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Browning, Logan, 1989 - 1991, 236143 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Cruikshank, Richard, 1979, 236142 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Harden, Edgar, 1985 July - 1987 June, 236141 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Hill, Draper, 1993 January - 1997 October, 236140 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Humanities Research Center, 1978 April 3 - 1978 May 23, 236139 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Johnson, Christopher, 1972 November 21 - 1972 August 22, 236138 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Huntington Library, 1985 December 13, 236137 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Kohler Books, Ltd., 1974 April 30 - 1974 September 10, 236136 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Möller, Joachim, 1989 October 9 - 1991 September 28, 236135 (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - National Humanities Center, 1988 October 17, 236134 (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Proudfoot, Karen, 1978 April 20 - 1982 March 15, 236133 (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - Research assistants, 1980 May - 1981 December, 236132 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Princeton, 1966 September - 1978 August, 236131 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Smith, Hazel, 1994 September - 1995 October, 236130 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Sotheby's, 1977 June - 1978 March, 236129 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Times Literary Supplement, 1988 February - 1988 July, 236128 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - UCLA, 1973 January - 1977 July, 236127 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Wardroper, John, 1991 June - 1997 July, 236126 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Sub-series B: Photocopies, notes and correspondence relating to George Cruikshank materials and collections, arranged alphabetically by repository or location (state). The files contain correspondence and many contain photocopies and transcriptions of Cruikshank material. Dates for the transcriptions and photocopies are noted if applicable, 1821-1991, 236059
    - Alabama, Alaska, Arizona, Arkansas, Arizona, 1977 June 7, 236124 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Arizona (photocopy), 1872 July 11, 236123 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Benjamin-Carnegie, New York (photocopy), 1849-1873, 236122 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Bodleian, Oxford, 1988 May - 1991 July, 236121 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - British Library, London (photocopies and notes), 1849 January - March 1982, 236120 (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - British Museum, 1966-1975, 236119 (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - California (transcriptions), 1832 - 1875, 236118 (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - California, 1977 June 7 - 1977 July 18, 236117 (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Colorado (transcriptions), 1831-1849, 236116 (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - Colorado, Connecticut, Delaware, D.C., 1977 February - 1977 August, 236115 (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - Connecticut (transcritions, photocopies), 1826-1878, 236114 (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - Delaware, 1977 August 1 - 1977 October 13, 236113 (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - District of Columbia (transcriptions), 1865, 236112 (Box 40, Folder 20)
    - England, undated, 236111 (Box 40, Folder 21)
    - Free Library, Philadelphia (transcriptions, photocopies), 1840-1872, 236110 (Box 40, Folder 22)
    - Florida, Georgia, Hawaii, University of Idaho, 1977 June - July, 236109 (Box 40, Folder 23)
    - Garber – Maryland (photocopies), 1868-1872, 236108 (Box 40, Folder 24)
    - Huntington Library (transcriptions), 1821-1870, 236107 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Illinois (transcriptions, photocopies), 1851-1874, 236106 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Illinois, Indiana, 1977 June 7 - 1977 August 1, 236105 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Indiana (transcriptions, photocopies), 1838-1853, 236104 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Iowa (transcriptions, photocopy), 1869, 236103 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Iowa, Kansas, 1977 August 9, 236102 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - John Rylands Library, 1974 August - 1978 June, 236101 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Kentucky (transcriptions, photocopies), 1850-1878, 236100 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Kentucky, Louisiana, 1977 June 22 - 1978 July 13, 236099 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Lilly Library, undated, 236098 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - London (photocopies), 1830-1875, 236097 (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Manchester, England (transcriptions, photocopies), 1850-1875, 236096 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - Maine, Maryland, 1977 June 7 - 1977 September 2, 236095 (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - Maryland (transcriptions, photocopies), 1823, 236094 (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Massachusetts (photocopies, 1832-871) and correspondence, 1971 June 14, 236093 (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - Massachusetts, Michigan, 1977 June 7 - 1977 August 17, 236092 (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - Michigan, undated, 236091 (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - Middlesex, England (transcriptions, photocopies), 1854 November - 1860 November, 236090 (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - Minnesota, 1977 June 7 - 1977 July 27, 236089 (Box 41, Folder 19)
    - Missouri, 1977 August, 236088 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - National Library of Scotland (transcriptions, photocopies), 1828-1872, 236087 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - New York Public Library, undated, 236086 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - New York, 1977 June 7 - July 8, 236085 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Nebraska, New Hampshire, 1977 June - July, 236084 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - New Jersey, New Mexico, 1977 July 12 - October 18, 236083 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - North Carolina (transcriptions, photocopies), 1843-1872, 236082 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - North Carolina, North Dakota, 1977 June 29, 236081 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Ohio (photocopies), 1969 February 13, 236080 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Ohio, Oklahoma, 1977 June 7-August 17, 236079 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Oregon, Pennsylvania, Rhode Island, 1977 June 7 - 1979 June 31, 236078 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Oxon, England (transcriptions of the Wilson collection), 1823-1893, 236077 (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Pennsylvania (transcriptions), 1841-1877, 236076 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - Penn State (transcriptions), 1842-1878, 236075 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Piermont Morgan Library, 1981 March - 1987 September, 236074 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Rice University, Woodson Research Center (transcriptions, photocopies), 1845, 1868, 236073 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Rochester, 1991 June 14, 236072 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Rosenbach Foundation, 1977 June - 1978 April, 236071 (Box 43, Folder 5)